<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>retro on Amiga blog</title>
    <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/tags/retro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in retro on Amiga blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 17:46:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/tags/retro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tactical RPGs</title>
      <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/tactical-rpgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 17:46:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/tactical-rpgs/</guid>
      <description></description>
      <content></content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retro Games</title>
      <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/retro-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 17:06:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/retro-games/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m off work recovering from surgery at the moment and during that time my interest in retro games has deepened quite a bit. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a long time with the Amiga mini and cataloguing old classic games on there and I&amp;rsquo;ve also spent time setting up Retro arch on my Linux box and Emudeck on my Steam Deck.
At first I was interested because of the history of games. It&amp;rsquo;s really interesting to see how they&amp;rsquo;ve developed over time, and I always find it fascinating when new genres emerge that were possible on old hardware but just nobody thought of it.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m off work recovering from surgery at the moment and during that time my interest in retro games has deepened quite a bit. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a long time with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/a500mini/&#34;&gt;Amiga mini and cataloguing old classic games on there&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;ve also spent time setting up &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.retroarch.com/&#34;&gt;Retro arch&lt;/a&gt; on my Linux box and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emudeck.com/&#34;&gt;Emudeck&lt;/a&gt; on my Steam Deck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I was interested because of the history of games. It&amp;rsquo;s really interesting to see how they&amp;rsquo;ve developed over time, and I always find it fascinating when new genres emerge that were possible on old hardware but just nobody thought of it. You couldn&amp;rsquo;t make a bombastic game like Call of Duty on a 48K Spectrum, but you could have made a survival game, in the vein of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Starve&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Starve&lt;/a&gt;. Nobody thought of it. Or maybe they did, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of it, and the genre lay dormant through the 16 + 32 bit years only to reemerge later, which is kind of interesting in itself. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1001_Video_Games_You_Must_Play_Before_You_Die&#34;&gt;1001 videogames to play before you die&lt;/a&gt; which I love because it&amp;rsquo;s in chronological order, and it&amp;rsquo;s just really interesting to see the artform evolve over time. Ditto the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitmapbooks.com/products/commodore-amiga-a-visual-commpendium&#34;&gt;Amiga&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitmapbooks.com/products/commodore-amiga-a-visual-commpendium&#34;&gt;SNES&lt;/a&gt; Bitmap books, which are absolutely beautiful, also in chronological order, and you can see how things changed even within one platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time I realised that part of the fun is making everything work. I remember when I was a kid with my Amiga you&amp;rsquo;d fiddle around with the software until it broke, and then have fun putting it back to how it was before you broke it. It&amp;rsquo;s sort of the same satisfaction I get with my job (data scientist), either taking something that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work and making it work, or even, yes sometimes I do break something (like the server) and have to put it right. There is so much to know about emulators, and BIOS&amp;rsquo;s, and scraping game information and I&amp;rsquo;m just sort of immersed in it along with the games themselves- the best Neo Geo games, the evolution of the shooter, the different graphical styles of (say) the Megadrive and SNES.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And at the end of it I like to write it all down. I&amp;rsquo;d be amazed if more than five people ever read the words I&amp;rsquo;m typing right now, but I&amp;rsquo;m really not writing to be read. I don&amp;rsquo;t ever feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve understood something properly until I&amp;rsquo;ve written it down, I&amp;rsquo;m the same at work- I like to catalogue and codify everything and then just stick it on the internet in case it helps someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I may pivot this blog to &amp;ldquo;Amigas and retro games&amp;rdquo;, perhaps, I hardly want separate blogs about each, and spend some time talking about the history and evolution of games as well as how to play them with modern hardware (one day I shall treat myself to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://polymega.com/&#34;&gt;Polymega&lt;/a&gt;, no doubt, but that day has not come yet). In any case, this post serves as a very long winded introduction to a post I&amp;rsquo;ve already decided to produce, all about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/c64-special/&#34;&gt;C64 mini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
