<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Amiga blog</title>
    <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Amiga blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 18:17:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amos</title>
      <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/amos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 18:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/amos/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my programming post I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with AMOS, because it&amp;rsquo;s AMOS that defeated me all those years ago with Space Invaders. There is stuff scattered about to help you learn and install AMOS but honestly it&amp;rsquo;s spread pretty thinly and there are quite a lot of broken links so I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bit of a frustrating start. I&amp;rsquo;m going to write down What I Did for everyone&amp;rsquo;s benefit, including mine when I get stuck.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/programming/&#34;&gt;programming post&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with AMOS, because it&amp;rsquo;s AMOS that defeated me all those years ago with Space Invaders. There is stuff scattered about to help you learn and install AMOS but honestly it&amp;rsquo;s spread pretty thinly and there are quite a lot of broken links so I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bit of a frustrating start. I&amp;rsquo;m going to write down What I Did for everyone&amp;rsquo;s benefit, including mine when I get stuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy AMOS/ Normal AMOS can be found in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/Commodore_Amiga_TOSEC_2012_04_10&#34;&gt;big archive of Amiga software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/marc365/AMOS-Professional-365/releases/tag/365&#34;&gt;AMOS Professional&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.retro-commodore.eu/download.php?file=Mandarian_Easy_Amos.pdf&#34;&gt;Easy AMOS manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.retro-commodore.eu/download.php?file=Mandarin_Amos_The_Creator_User_Guide.pdf&#34;&gt;AMOS manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.classicamiga.com/images/stories/jreviews/software/A/manuals/AmosPro.pdf&#34;&gt;AMOS Professional manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/amiga-game-makers-manual/mode/2up&#34;&gt;Amiga game maker&amp;rsquo;s manual with AMOS basic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://retro-commodore.eu/files/downloads/amigamanuals-xiik.net/eBooks/Mastering%20Amiga%20Amos%20-%20eBook-ENG.pdf&#34;&gt;Mastering Amiga AMOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/amigasourcecodepreservation/ultimate-amos/-/raw/master/pdf/ultimate-amos-1994-holborn.pdf&#34;&gt;Ultimate AMOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to give instructions that work on FS-UAE for Linux, which is what I&amp;rsquo;m using. I imagine it will be even simpler on a real Amiga. As for other types of Amigas, I really have no idea what I&amp;rsquo;m doing so don&amp;rsquo;t listen to me. Speaking of not knowing what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, I&amp;rsquo;m still sort of bobbing about trying to find the path of least resistance to learn this stuff, these are only notes really, hopefully in the future it will all make sense and I&amp;rsquo;ll write a follow up post that makes more sense. I will &lt;em&gt;try&lt;/em&gt; to put stuff on GitHub, but how the heck you get stuff from AMOS onto GitHub on an FS-UAE emulated instance of an Amiga I don&amp;rsquo;t at the moment have a clue. If I write something that works and figure it out, it will be here, trust me on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easy-amos&#34;&gt;Easy AMOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started working through the manual of Easy AMOS. It&amp;rsquo;s very readable and accessible, but for someone who knows how to program (badly) it was a bit &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; basic. It&amp;rsquo;s all in there, I just wanted to move through the material a bit faster. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know how to program and you feel like learning a 29 year old programming language on an emulated version of hardware that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been manufactured in 26 years (not sure how many people there are in &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; Venn diagram) go for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;normal-amos&#34;&gt;Normal AMOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;//TODO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;amos-professional&#34;&gt;AMOS Professional&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting AMOS Professional working is very easy. Go to the link above and download the zip file where indicated. Extract it, and you just want the folder called &amp;ldquo;AMOS&amp;rdquo;. Copy that folder somewhere you can keep it, then just drop it in as a hard drive in FS-UAE (go to the hard drive tab, select the little picture of a folder next to an empty hard drive slot, and then select the AMOS folder). You&amp;rsquo;ll need to have a Workbench HD image too. That&amp;rsquo;s another blog post. I learned the above in these &lt;a href=&#34;https://retrogamecoders.com/installing-amos-basic/&#34;&gt;excellent blog posts&lt;/a&gt; but the advice is in a video and I prefer to read stuff myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next step is to work through the tutorials in the previous link which culminates in&amp;hellip; yes&amp;hellip; Space Invaders. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to count that as a &amp;ldquo;win&amp;rdquo; for this step though, I&amp;rsquo;ll make my own. Good start though.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming</title>
      <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 22:14:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/programming/</guid>
      <description>If you read my introduction then you&amp;rsquo;ll know that part of the reason I&amp;rsquo;m doing this blog, doing any of this in fact, is because I tried to write Space Invaders in AMOS 25 years ago, got a weird bug, and gave up. More for my reference than anything else (like 95% of my GitHub, in fact), here follows a list of the options I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at so far</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;If you read &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/intro/&#34;&gt;my introduction&lt;/a&gt; then you&amp;rsquo;ll know that part of the reason I&amp;rsquo;m doing this blog, doing any of this in fact, is because I tried to write Space Invaders in AMOS 25 years ago, got a weird bug, and gave up. More for my reference than anything else (like 95% of my GitHub, in fact), here follows a list of the options I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at so far&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seem to be a few options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMOS (which comes in Easy and Professional form, as well as normal AMOS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BlitzBasic (which got to version 2 but now seems to have been upgraded to the related 3, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amiblitz.de/index.php&#34;&gt;which looks pretty swish&lt;/a&gt; with an IDE and everything)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C (I would love to learn C but I gather it&amp;rsquo;s pretty hard)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assembler (I&amp;rsquo;ve read Assembler and it looks like what most people think normal programming languages look like- gobbledigook)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty much going to work down the list, I think, I&amp;rsquo;m going to go give BlitzBasic 3 a try, probably will bounce off that and then try C. But who knows? This is pretty fun, could end up anywhere. I highly doubt I will write a line of Amiga Assembler in my life but never say never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I should add is that I really want to write the code on an Amiga. An emulated one at the moment, and then perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll treat myself to a Vampire some time. I don&amp;rsquo;t have much room in the office but Vampires are pretty small. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to write games &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; the Amiga, I want to write them &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; the Amiga. You know, for old time&amp;rsquo;s sake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next post is I think one aimed at my buddies, entitled, &amp;ldquo;So you want to play Amiga games without buying any new hardware?&amp;rdquo; (super easy and cheap).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
