<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Amiga blog</title>
    <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Amiga blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 22:14:57 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programming</title>
      <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 22:14:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/programming/</guid>
      <description>If you read my introduction then you&amp;rsquo;ll know that part of the reason I&amp;rsquo;m doing this blog, doing any of this in fact, is because I tried to write Space Invaders in AMOS 25 years ago, got a weird bug, and gave up. More for my reference than anything else (like 95% of my GitHub, in fact), here follows a list of the options I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at so far</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;If you read &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/intro/&#34;&gt;my introduction&lt;/a&gt; then you&amp;rsquo;ll know that part of the reason I&amp;rsquo;m doing this blog, doing any of this in fact, is because I tried to write Space Invaders in AMOS 25 years ago, got a weird bug, and gave up. More for my reference than anything else (like 95% of my GitHub, in fact), here follows a list of the options I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at so far&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seem to be a few options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMOS (which comes in Easy and Professional form, as well as normal AMOS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BlitzBasic (which got to version 2 but now seems to have been upgraded to the related 3, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amiblitz.de/index.php&#34;&gt;which looks pretty swish&lt;/a&gt; with an IDE and everything)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C (I would love to learn C but I gather it&amp;rsquo;s pretty hard)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assembler (I&amp;rsquo;ve read Assembler and it looks like what most people think normal programming languages look like- gobbledigook)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty much going to work down the list, I think, I&amp;rsquo;m going to go give BlitzBasic 3 a try, probably will bounce off that and then try C. But who knows? This is pretty fun, could end up anywhere. I highly doubt I will write a line of Amiga Assembler in my life but never say never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I should add is that I really want to write the code on an Amiga. An emulated one at the moment, and then perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll treat myself to a Vampire some time. I don&amp;rsquo;t have much room in the office but Vampires are pretty small. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to write games &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; the Amiga, I want to write them &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; the Amiga. You know, for old time&amp;rsquo;s sake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next post is I think one aimed at my buddies, entitled, &amp;ldquo;So you want to play Amiga games without buying any new hardware?&amp;rdquo; (super easy and cheap).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
