<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>games on Amiga blog</title>
    <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/tags/games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in games on Amiga blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 17:24:16 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A500 mini games roundup</title>
      <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/a500mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 17:24:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/a500mini/</guid>
      <description>A500 mini- built in games roundup The A500 mini is here. Much has been written about it already so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to say too much about it, but I was halfway through a post about it when I realised it might be fun just to give my recommendations for the best games on the unit. In truth the games are quite disappointing and there are loads of classics which are missing.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a500-mini--built-in-games-roundup&#34;&gt;A500 mini- built in games roundup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://retrogames.biz/products/thea500-mini&#34;&gt;A500 mini&lt;/a&gt; is here. Much has been written about it already so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to say too much about it, but I was halfway through a post about it when I realised it might be fun just to give my recommendations for the best games on the unit. In truth the games are quite disappointing and there are loads of classics which are missing. I think the problem comes down to getting rights to the games. When Nintendo made the mini SNES they put their best first party games on it and made a tidy packet from doing so. But my guess here is that a lot of games which are either licensed or might be expected to sell elsewhere are not on because the original IP holder wants to protect the revenue from selling the game elsewhere. This is quite understandable, of course. Anyway, there&amp;rsquo;s another post where I talk about the brilliant games that are not on the unit and how to get them, but for now let&amp;rsquo;s look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://retrogames.biz/games/thea500-mini/&#34;&gt;games that are on there&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stone-cold-classic&#34;&gt;Stone cold classic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alien Breed: Special Edition 92
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is basically Aliens: The Topdown shooter. Atmospheric, well paced, exciting, varied. Truly a masterpiece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinball Dreams
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is what the people who make Battlefield were doing in the 1990s, making pinball games. The tables are a little simplistic and small by modern standards and there&amp;rsquo;s only one standout table (Nightmare) but it&amp;rsquo;s still brilliant. The sequel, Pinball Fantasies, is better in every way and this can be added to the A500 mini, for more on which see a forthcoming post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speedball 2: Brutal Deluxe
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A futuristic sport that basically involves hitting people and chucking a ball in a goal this will always raise a smile in multiplayer. It&amp;rsquo;s weaker for single players, as these things often are, but there is a career mode that is actually reasonably deep considering what a silly sport it is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worms: The Director’s Cut
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worms. Brilliant on every format, ever. I never played the Amiga version back in the day so I&amp;rsquo;ve had a quick look for this post.  WHAT DO I THINK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Chaos Engine
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top down co-op shooter with beautiful graphics. A little primitive by today&amp;rsquo;s standards but still brilliant to this day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;worth-a-look&#34;&gt;Worth a look&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATR: All Terrain Racing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;California Games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paradroid 90&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another World&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arcade Pool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dont-bother&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t bother&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle Chess
Zool: Ninja Of The ”Nth” Dimension
Kick Off 2&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
