<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Terminal</title>
    <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 18:45:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intro and welcome</title>
      <link>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 18:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisbeeley.github.io/amiga_blog/posts/intro/</guid>
      <description>Hello! This blog is all about my return to the world of Amiga. I have been clicking occasionally on Amiga stuff that I saw in my Twitter feed and was amazed to see that an Amiga print magazine was being launched in the UK. I was an avid user of the Amiga from about 1988 until about 1995. It was a really important part of my life and the hours of messing around I used to do with Workbench to get everything working are probably partly the reason why I do the job that I do (data scientist, which I absolutely love).</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Hello! This blog is all about my return to the world of Amiga. I have been clicking occasionally on Amiga stuff that I saw in my Twitter feed and was amazed to see that an Amiga print magazine was being launched in the UK. I was an avid user of the Amiga from about 1988 until about 1995. It was a really important part of my life and the hours of messing around I used to do with Workbench to get everything working are probably partly the reason why I do the job that I do (data scientist, which I absolutely love). I might do a nostalgic trip through what growing up with Amiga (500, then 1200 with 60MB hard drive :smile: )&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
